# **Chris** Slater

Hello! I'm Chris. A Senior Web Developer specializing in front end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects, I am well-versed in a number of programming languages but have a significant love for JavaScript!

Snapper Fish LTD
Office 7
35-37 Ludgate Hill
London
EC4M 7JN
020 3290 3474
hello@snapper.fish
www.snapper.fish

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Amido,** London — React and Javascript Developer

June 2015 - PRESENT

- Architected and Front end led a ReactJS and Flux project, delivering a 'real time' cricket manager MMO browser game, complete with leagues, team management, player fatigue, stadiums, Facebook integration and more!
- Architected a re-design for CBRE's high-end commercial and residential property map search and listing SPA. I was also involved in training developers in Flux best practices and preparing them on re-structuring their Flux workflow to benefit from ReduxJS single state store.
- Built vanilla javascript SDK's for ASOS, providing api-to-client middleware for web and mobile platforms.

## Rated People, London — Senior Web Developer

NOVEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2015

- Pitched and Tech Led the rebuild of customer logged in experiences, from a custom javascript MVC into Backbone.js and Node.js. The application included sections such as profiles, member benefits, subscriptions, search, gmaps and purchasing.
- Built and maintained loyalty and benefit web applications in Symfony and jQuery
- Tutored Junior developers on how to architect their Javascript and CSS using Object Oriented approaches.

## **IPC MEDIA,** London — Digital Developer

AUGUST 2011 - NOVEMBER 2013

- Developed a media rich parallax site for Chambord, promoting just how nice it is with cocktails!
- Developed a blog site in Symfony for Coca Cola, promoting fashion StyleItLight
- Developed SPA's for a number of clients, including: Estée Lauder, Kelloggs, Tesco, TRESemmé and Remmington. These were built using a of combination of jQuery, Symfony, Action Script and/or Drupal.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### **Javascript**

- React
- Redux
- Flux
- Node
- Backbone
- Keystone
- Webpack
- Gulp
- Grunt

#### **Testing**

- Mocha
- Chai
- Sinon
- Jasmine
- Enzyme

#### **HTML & CSS**

- HTML
- CSS
- POSTCSS
- SCSS
- LESS
- SMACSS

#### **Continuous Integration**

- Jenkins
- Travis
- Appveyor
- TeamCity

#### **Version Control**

- GIT
- SVN

## **Moore Wilson,** Salisbury — Drupal Developer

MARCH 2011 - AUGUST 2011

 Built Drupal 7 sites for Interoute, Chatham House and Centre of European Reform (CER).

### **Opportunity Links,** Cambridge — Drupal Developer

DECEMBER 2010 - MARCH 2011

### **i2 Limited,** Cambridge — Webmaster

JULY 2010 - NOVEMBER 2010

# **Burgate School,** Fordingbridge — Assistant Network Manager

NOVEMBER 2009 - SEPTEMBER 2010

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Anglia Ruskin University,** Cambridge — *Internet Technology*

2007 - 2009

First Class with Honours

## **Burgate School and Sixth form,** Location — A-levels

2003 - 2005

- Computing
- Business Studies
- Government & Politics

#### **Others**

- Agile
- Docker
- Symfony
- Drupal